(a) (503) 995 6784 **(a)** aslibrhin@gmail.com • **(b)** Oakland, CA https://github.com/berhane011

Summary

Seasoned UI/UX designer with 4+ years experience in building, maintaining and designing responsive websites.

I am proficient in React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and jQuery. I love learning new domains, and easily adapt to new environments, technologies and workflows.

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, ReactJS, CSS3, HTML5, Typescript, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Databases

MYSQL, MongoDB

Frameworks

Redux jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, WordPress, bulma, Adobe Photoshop & illustrator

Tools

Git/github, Heroku, Firebase, Node etc.

Work Experience

Front-End Develope R - Zemen, Addis ababa, Ethiopia - April 2017 - june 2018

- Developed both front-end and back-end features for apps using standard REST APIs, TDD/BDD, Intellij, JQuery, Spark in React, Java
 and IS
- developing responsive web applications across platforms using React in front end ,javaScript, Ajax,Axios,and Adobe photoshop
- analyzed UI/UX design for responsive layout for improved usability.
- creating Api endpoints to connect calls made from the front end to the databases and vice versa.
- Developed both front-end and back-end features for apps using standard REST APIs, TDD/BDD, Intellij, JQuery, Spark in React, Java and JS.

JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER (FULL TIME) - Dana IT, Eritrea - April 2016—Feb 2017

- Developed both front-end and back-end features for apps using standard REST APIs, TDD/BDD, Intellij, JQuery, Spark in React, Java and JS.
- Designed and built a web page which helps users to get filtered news according to their mood(positive,neutral and negative) using Vader sentiment ,HTML,CSS,JavaScript and React
- Developed applications, user interface, and RESTful API to be consumed by various modules.
- Work as part of a team as well as work autonomously.
- Rewrite existing code, and add new code on top of pre-existing code

Web Developer (Full time) - Absari enterprise, , Eritrea - Jan 2014 – Feb 2016

- Designed, developed and tested HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery and React.JS that meets accessibility and web browser standards for websites.
- Worked on responsive design and developed a single ISOMORPHIC responsive website that could be served to desktop, Tablets and mobile users using React.js.
- Improved & created new features on the project using react.js
- Designed and maintained an Eritrean website www.kebhi.com which Integrated all the frontend and backend components and used cloud storage for the backend.

Education

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP - UC Berkeley extension, California-2020 BSC in Computer science - Eritrean Institute of Technology, Eritrea- 2008-2013